<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading the Holy Land</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Reading the Holy Land</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 10:48:48 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptions</title>
      <link>/outputs/transcriptions/transcriptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 10:48:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outputs/transcriptions/transcriptions/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writers and Gratitude</title>
      <link>/blog/writers_and_gratitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 10:48:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/writers_and_gratitude/</guid>
      <description>Rorgo Fretellus&#39; description of the holy sites in and around Jerusalem - the Descriptio de locis sanctis - was one of the most popular Latin accounts of the Holy Land written during the time of the crusades. First composed in the late 1130s, there remain over a hundred manuscripts that attest to its popularity and wide diffusion. Yet in spite of this wealth of manuscript witnesses, many questions concerning this text and its author remain unresolved, and a critical edition of this work which would take into account its various redactions is still lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Everyone liked Pilgrimages</title>
      <link>/blog/not_everyone_liked_pilgrimages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 10:48:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/not_everyone_liked_pilgrimages/</guid>
      <description>As the RTHL team goes through catalogues in search of Latin works about the Holy Land written during the crusades, one often comes across interesting things. During the crusades, pilgrimage guides devoted to the Holy Land were a very popular genre. They were often written by travelers who occasionally reused material from earlier accounts. One such text is found in a thirteenth-century manuscript preserved at the British Library in London (MS Harley 2333).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Communications</title>
      <link>/outputs/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 10:48:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outputs/presentations/</guid>
      <description>José María Andrés Porras, &amp;ldquo;Presentation of the database of the ISF-funded Project ‘Reception of the Accounts of the Holy Land (12th-13th centuries),’&amp;rdquo; Minerva-Gentner Symposium, Bar-Ilan University, December 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 10:59:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email us</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Members</title>
      <link>/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 10:59:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/</guid>
      <description>Jonathan Rubin Jonathan Rubin teaches at the Department of Land of Israel Studies and Archaeology at Bar Ilan University, Israel. His work focuses on two main themes: the intellectual history of the Crusader Kingdom of Jerusalem and travel literature. Among his publications are: “The Manuscript Tradition of Burchard of Mount Sion’s Descriptio Terre Sancte,” The Journal of Medieval Latin 30 (2020), pp. 257-286; “Spiritual and Practical Instructions for Pilgrims: A Preliminary Presentation of Two Unknown Texts,” Mediterranean Historical Review 35.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/outputs/conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outputs/conferences/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/outputs/datasets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outputs/datasets/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/outputs/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outputs/publications/</guid>
      <description>Jonathan Rubin, “Notes on the Development and Reception of a Medieval Account of the Holy Land: Burchard of Mount Sion’s Descriptio Terre Sancte as a Test Case,” in New Directions in Latin Travel Literature [forthcoming in a volume to be published by De Gruyter in a series titled Das Mittelalter: Beihefte]</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
